Esta lição 22 de PEMSLO Inglês 1. Listen to this
conversation. Acabam de apresentar o senhor Johnson à senhora Martins.
Listen. Pleased to meet you, Mrs. Martins. Is your husband
here in New York too? Yes, he is, and the children are with us too.
How many children do you have? Three. We have three children,
one boy and two girls. That's our boy over there. And where
are your girls? They're at the hotel with my husband.
Listen again. Pleased to meet you, Mrs.
Martins. Is your husband here in New York too? Yes, he is,
and the children are with us too. How many children do you have?
Three. We have three children: one boy and two
girls. That's our boy over there. And where are your girls?
They're at the hotel with my husband. De agora em diante,
você vai ouvir com mais frequência as instruções em inglês. Tais como: Now
say in English. Olá. Agora diga em inglês
olá. Say olá.
Hello. Isto é
necessário para que você compreenda e fale inglês sem traduzir do português.
Talvez seja um pouco difícil no começo. Você pode repetir a
lição várias vezes se precisar. Say é um prazer conhecê-lo.
Pleased to meet you.
Ask me. Pergunte-me. Ask me.
Onde fica o banheiro?
Where's the bathroom?
Excuse me, where's the bathroom?
Ask me again.
Pergunte-me outra vez. Ask me again.
Where's the bathroom?
Say in English. Um menino grande.
A big boy.
Say. Nós temos um menino grande.
We have a big boy.
Nosso menino é grande.
Our boy is big.
Our boy's big.
Say uma menina pequena.
A little girl.
Nós também temos uma menina pequena.
We have a little girl too.
Say, nossa menina não é grande.
Our girl isn't big.
Say, ela é pequena.
She's little.
Ask, quantos filhos você tem?
How many children do you have?
Say that you have three children. Diga que vocês têm
três filhos.
We have three children.
Ask where they are. Pergunte onde eles estão.
Where are they? Where are they?
Say eles estão aqui conosco.
They are here with us.
With us. Minha família
está na América. Listen and repeat. My family
is in America.
America. In America.
My family's in America.
Say again. Diga outra vez. Minha família está
na América.
My family's in America.
Now say that your family's in Brazil. Now say
that your family's in Brazil.
My family's in Brazil.
Say that your family's with you.
My family's with me.
With me.
Now say, nossa família está conosco.
Our family's with us.
Our family's
with us.
Agora você quer perguntar quantas pessoas há na sua família?
Listen. How many people are there in your family?
Primeiro, quantas pessoas? Listen and repeat.
How many people?
People.
Poll. P. People.
How many people?
Ask in English. Quantas pessoas?
Agora você quer perguntar quantas pessoas há?
Listen and repeat. How many people are there?
Are there. There.
Are. Are there.
How many people?
How many people are there?
Ask. Quantas pessoas há?
Try to say. Tente dizer. Try to say.
Na sua família. In your family.
In. In your family,
quantas pessoas há?
How many people are there?
Try to say: Há quatro pessoas.
There are four people.
Try to say, na minha família.
In my family.
Say, há quatro pessoas na minha família.
There are four people in my family.
Quantas pessoas há na sua família?
How many people are there in your family?
Say that there are six people in your family.
There are six people in my family.
Nós temos duas meninas grandes.
We have two big girls.
Two big girls.
E dois meninos pequenos.
And two little boys.
Two little boys.
Nós temos uma família grande.
We have a big family.
Ask verdade?
Really?
Really? Say nós
podemos esperar. We can wait.
Ask, onde fica o banheiro?
Where's the bathroom?
Say that the bathroom is over there.
The bathroom is over there.
It's over there.
Agora é assim que se diz carro. Listen and repeat.
Car. Car. Say in
English. Carro.
Car. A car.
Try to say. Try to say. Eu tenho
um carro.
I have a car.
Now ask me if I have a car.
Agora pergunte-me se eu tenho um carro. Now ask
me if I have a car.
Do you have a car?
Como eu posso responder de uma forma curta que eu tenho um carro?
Yes, I do.
Now ask me if my car is here. If,
see. Now ask me if my car is here.
Is your car here?
Ask me if my family is in America.
Is your family in America?
Ou no
Brasil? Or in
Brazil? Say,
as crianças estão aqui conosco.
The children are here with us.
Ask me how many people there are in my family.
How many people are there in your family?
Say, há cinco pessoas na nossa família.
There are
five people in our
family. Say that you have a car.
我是有车的。We have
a car. Say that
you have a big car.
We have a big car.
Try to say, há muitos carros.
There are a lot of cars.
Há muitos carros grandes na América.
There are a lot of big cars in America.
Ask. Vihdaji.
Really? Ask where the bathroom is.
Where's the bathroom?
Do you know where the bathroom is?
Say three pessoas.
Three people.
Say há três pessoas.
There are three people.
Na nossa família.
In our family.
Responda afirmativamente à próxima pergunta usando
nós. Do you have a car? Do you have
Yes, we have a car.
Yes, we do.
Nós podemos esperar.
We can wait.
Você quer dizer nós gostaríamos de pôr gasolina.
Literalmente, nós gostaríamos de um pouco de gasolina.
Listen and repeat. We'd like some gas.
Gas.
Gas. Some gas.
Say again. Nós gostaríamos de pôr gasolina.
We'd like some gas.
Continue usando some gas em inglês, a não
ser que eu te diga o contrário. Agora diga outra vez: nós gostaríamos
de pôr gasolina.
We'd like some gas.
We'd like some gas, please.
Pergunte quanto custa.
How much is it?
Escute a sua resposta. It's two dollars per gallon.
Nos Estados Unidos, a medida para líquidos é o galão. Um galão
é o equivalente a três litros e meio. Escute e repita: galão.
Gallon. Gallon.
Gallon.
Gallon. Dois dólares
por galão. Listen and repeat. Two dollars per gallon.
Gallon. Per.
Per. Per gallon.
Two dollars per gallon.
É claro que os preços variam de lugar para lugar e em diferentes épocas.
Mas por agora diga dois dólares por galão.
Two dollars per gallon.
It's two dollars per gallon.
A gasolina custa dois dólares por galão. Ao falar
de gasolina em geral, você diz gas em inglês e
não some gas.
Gas is two dollars per gallon.
Say, "Isperdi." Wait.
Wait.
La. Over there.
Usando o número, diga: Custa um dólar por
It's one dollar per gallon.
One dollar per gallon.
Over there, it's one dollar per gallon.
Try to ask. Try to ask.
Quanta gasolina você quer?
How much gas do you want?
Quando os americanos colocam gasolina, eles às vezes enchem o
seu próprio tanque. Ou eles podem pedir para um empregado do posto para fazê-lo.
É assim que se diz: enche o tanque, por favor. Escute e repita
parte por parte. Up.
Up. It.
Fill.
Fill it. Fill it
up. Fill it up, please.
Say again. Enche o tanque, por favor.
Fill it up, please.
Say espere.
Wait, please wait.
Agora tente perguntar: Você tem gasolina suficiente?
Do you have enough gas?
Enough gas?
Responda brevemente que não.
No, I don't.
No, I don't have enough gas.
Try to say: Eu vou colocar gasolina.
Diga literalmente: Eu vou comprar um pouco de gasolina.
I'm going to buy some gas.
I'm going
to buy some gas.
Quanto custa?
How much is it?
Custa dois dólares por galão.
It's two dollars per gallon.
Sei. Então enche o tanque, por favor.
Then fill it up, please.
A medida de distância usada nos Estados Unidos é a milha.
Uma milha equivalente a um pouco mais de um quilômetro e meio.
É assim que se diz milha em inglês. Listen and
Mile. Mile. Mile.
Try to ask: Quantas milhas?
How many miles?
Miles. How many miles?
Answer: Responda. Answer: Cinquenta
milhas. Fifty miles.
Say: Então eu vou colocar gasolina.
Then I'm going to buy some gas.
Educadamente, peça para o empregado do posto para encher o tanque.
Fill it up, please.
Agora o homem diz: Eu vou para Long Island.
Long Island. Listen and repeat. Long Island.
Lund. Lund.
I, Lund.
Island.
Long. Long Island.
Long Island.
Long Island. É uma região de Nova York onde há muitas
praias. Eu vou para Long Island. Listen and repeat again.
I'm going to Long Island.
To Long Island.
To. I'm going to Long Island.
Say again. Eu vou para Long Island.
I'm going to Long Island.
Try to ask: Quantas milhas são?
Literalmente, quantas milhas é?
How many miles is it?
It. Is it? How many miles
How many miles is it to Long Island?
Answer: Sesenta miles.
Sixty miles.
It's 60 miles.
It's 60 miles to Long Island.
Ask how many miles it is to Long Island.
How many miles is it to Long Island?
To Long Island.
Answer: 65 miles.
65 miles.
It's 65 miles to Long Island.
Há seis pessoas na nossa família.
There are six people in our family.
Eu tenho um carro grande.
I have a big car.
E eu tenho muita gasolina.
And I have a lot of gas.
Try to say. E nós vamos para Long Island.
And we're going to Long Island.
We're going to Long Island.
Nesta lição de Inglês 1 se incluem exercícios de leitura.